<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>poem on Challen</title>
    <link>/tags/poem/</link>
    <description>Recent content in poem on Challen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>ChallenAi</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 01:28:16 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/poem/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Asia Poem: Meng(氓)</title>
      <link>/posts/inspiration/meng/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 01:28:16 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/inspiration/meng/</guid>
      <description>This poem are selected from &amp;lsquo;the story of songs&amp;rsquo; which is written in about 300 AC, almost the same time with &amp;lsquo;the art of war&amp;rsquo; which is more famous than the former.
Inspiration The reason I translate this is I read an article (Why Women Sometimes Give Up On Men They Love)[https://psiloveyou.xyz/why-women-will-leave-men-they-love-a320d1e33c44] It remind me of a love story almost 2000 years ago in a totally diffirent culture.
Let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at this story.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;This poem are selected from &amp;lsquo;the story of songs&amp;rsquo; which is written in about 300 AC, almost the same time with &amp;lsquo;the art of war&amp;rsquo; which is more famous than the former.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;inspiration&#34;&gt;Inspiration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason I translate this is I read an article (Why Women Sometimes Give Up On Men They Love)[https://psiloveyou.xyz/why-women-will-leave-men-they-love-a320d1e33c44]
It remind me of a love story almost 2000 years ago in a totally diffirent culture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at this story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-one&#34;&gt;Chapter One&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A man looks attractive comes to me,
use his cloth to swap my silk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But he doesn&amp;rsquo;t want the silk,
his target is me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m about to accompany with him to the River Qi when we seperate,
but we finally arrived at Hill Dunqu.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t want to delay our marriage inside my heart,
but you(the man) never make a formal propose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please don&amp;rsquo;t be angry,
I promise you autumn is the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-two&#34;&gt;Chapter Two&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I miss you so sick,
I stand in the city wall to look for you,
I can feel my smile so bright when I find you,
I can also feel my pain if you don&amp;rsquo;t appear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You ask for fortune-teller to divine our future, It&amp;rsquo;s bright,
so I enter your carriage and get married without doubt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-three&#34;&gt;Chapter Three&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the leaf of mulbery hasn&amp;rsquo;t withered,
it looks colorful.
(When I&amp;rsquo;m still young, I looks beautiful.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Turtledove, don&amp;rsquo;t eat too much mulbery fruit.
Gril, don&amp;rsquo;t fall too deep in love.
(Chinese myth says the turtledove will get poisoning when it eats too much mulbery fruit)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a man fall in love, he can still leave,
if a woman fall in love, she will get trapped.
(In the traditional society, if a woman has married with someone, she is really hard to remarry with someone else when divorced, the man is totally different)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-four&#34;&gt;Chapter Four&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now the leafs of mulbery has withered,
they fall down from the limb.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I came to your family,
my life became poor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;River Qi runs day and night,
it wets the curtain of my carriage (when I decide to leave you).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have no fault in my behavior,
but you are inconsistent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;chapter-five&#34;&gt;Chapter Five&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After I become your wife, I work hard for our family;
I go to bed late, I wake up early.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(However, we often have conflict.)
Since the verbally abusive ends,
the family violence starts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brothers are not wise enough,
laugh loudly at me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I stay alone and calm down to consider about myself,
how sad I am!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;chapter-six&#34;&gt;Chapter Six&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;River Qi looks so board, but it still has its border.
Swamp Xi looks so large, but it also has its end.
(so do I.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still remember my warm family time
when I&amp;rsquo;m a little girl.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though once we own the swear and promise from each other,
we stand in different sides now,
I will never think about you again,
it&amp;rsquo;s end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;mordern-situation&#34;&gt;mordern situation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lucky part is nowadays, we can easily devorce without to much limit,
especially in the western society.(Asian countries are usually much traditional.)
However, marriage is a serious topic, not only about outlooking, money,
the same story happens everyday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I read the article before,
I can feel her pain.
But my opinion is don&amp;rsquo;t give your husband/wife advice to listen to you, or try to change his personality.
Instead, find someone really cares about you,
natually he will talk and listen to you, about dreams, future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;original post here:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://challenai.medium.com/a-love-story-from-distant-eastern-world-8de422cb0e53&#34;&gt;https://challenai.medium.com/a-love-story-from-distant-eastern-world-8de422cb0e53&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Asia Poem: Rain Watcher(听雨)</title>
      <link>/posts/inspiration/rain/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 01:28:16 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/inspiration/rain/</guid>
      <description>content Listen to the rain in the party when I&amp;rsquo;m young. I can see the light of red candles reflected from curtain cover.
Listen to the rain in a floating boat when I&amp;rsquo;m an adult. I can see the wild goose fly against the west wind between board river and low cloudy sky.
But now I listen to the rain under the eaves of a temple. my hair has partly turned white.</description>
      <content>&lt;h2 id=&#34;content&#34;&gt;content&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Listen to the rain in the party when I&amp;rsquo;m young.
I can see the light of red candles reflected from curtain cover.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Listen to the rain in a floating boat when I&amp;rsquo;m an adult.
I can see the wild goose fly against the west wind
between board river and low cloudy sky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But now I listen to the rain under the eaves of a temple.
my hair has partly turned white.
God seems has no emotion about our sadness and happiness, leave or reunion.
I hear the rain from dusk to dawn, one drop by another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-simple-mordern-version&#34;&gt;A simple mordern version&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I&amp;rsquo;m young, I enjoy the party, the indulging atmosphere makes me crazy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I&amp;rsquo;m an adult, I leave home to find better oppotunity, I have ambition when I&amp;rsquo;m on the way to future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that I have experienced too much,
I sit in a temple and care nothing about outside world.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
